你愛上她了吧?
Are you in love with her?
喔! 才沒有 別說了 爸
Whoa! No, shut up, Dad.
什么?      我要么作為自己去
What?        No, I either go as me
要么就不去了
or I'm not going at all.
不 滾開 想得美 蠢逼
No! Fuck off! Moron.
你不可能永遠不認我的
You can't...you can't deny me for ever, you know.
我還就不認了
Well, denied, mate!
是移植的肺
It was the lung transplant.
給了我操掉別人超能力的能力
I've got the power to fuck powers out of people.
喂 喂 我有事跟你談
Whoa! Whoa! I need to talk to you!
是關于一件毛衣的
It's about a jumper!
早安 費利
Morning, Finlay!
不是吧
Oh, come on!
我操 是真的
That's...that's fucking it.
他滾蛋了
He's fucked off!
他離開我了
He's left me!
魯迪二號跑了 離開我了
Rudy 2's buggered off and left me!
他去哪了?      不知道 兩天沒見了
Where's he gone?        I don't know. He's been gone a couple of days.
我以為他會回來過夜 可他沒回
I thought he might come back in the night, but he's not.
他頭一次從我分離這么久
He's never been out of me this long before.
這是我的褲子嗎?
Are they my trousers?
對 該死 抱歉
Yeah. Shit. I'm sorry.
我正要問你借點衣服
I was going to ask if I could borrow some clothes,
我沒得穿了
because I've run out!
你打算怎么辦?      操 我才不管呢
What you gonna do?        Fuck, I'm not gonna do nothing.
他想一個人去忙他的 隨便他
If he wants go off and do his own thing, that's his decision.
謝天謝地 我說 終于自由了
Good riddance. That's what I say. Frigging free at last!
老天開眼啊 我終于自由啦      別...
Thank fuck almighty, I'm free at last.         Don't...
快住手
Stop it.
-==破爛熊樂園傾情奉獻==-
本字幕僅供學習交流，嚴禁用于商業用途
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
超能少年 第五季第4集
-=破爛熊字幕組=-
翻譯：tpring
校對：tpring
時間軸：Dot_Kuma
大衛﹒西蒙斯 是我一個同學 他長了尾巴
David Simmonds, right? Now, he was a kid at our school. He had a tail.
就好像脊椎末端長了塊沒用的皮
It was like a useless flap of skin at the base of his spine.
終于有一天 他把尾巴摘掉了
And one day, he had the bloody tail removed.
那就是我現在的感覺
And now I know how he feels.
摘掉尾巴了 伙計們 我們干了吧
To losing your tail, guys. Let's get in there.
可他是我們的一員
But he was part of the gang.
得了吧
For fuck's sake!
你是史酷比 他是小皮(史酷比的侄子)
He was Scrappy-Doo to your Scooby.
你當然是夏奇(史酷比的飼主)
You're Shaggy. Obviously.
那我是哪個?
Um...which one am I?
薇瑪      薇瑪?
Velma.        Velma?
嗯      戴眼鏡那個?
Mm.        With the glasses?
嗯      扯淡
Mm.        Fuck off.
要是他把自己弄死了呢?
What if he's killed himself?
他為啥要自殺啊 費恩?
W-Why the fuck would he have killed himself, Finn?
他也不想的
He didn't mean to.
吃著橘子 戴上狗項圈 捆緊點 再緊點
Satsuma in the mouth. Dog collar on. Bit tighter, bit tighter.
夠了啊
Fuck's sake!
我走 我自己慶祝去 好了吧?
I'll piss off and I'll frigging celebrate by myself, shall I?
滾草
Fuck you.
你也滾草
Fuck...you.
Fuck you.
好好休息
Have a nice evening.
好白的屁股
That is a really pale arse.
你們干什么啊?
What the fuck, guys?
啊      好了
Aah!        OK.
老天 我怎么沒在床上?
Christ sake! Why am I not in bed?
早安
Morning.
早安 啊
Morning! Ah!
這都怪魯迪二號
This is...this is Rudy 2's fault!
我怎么能照顧自己呢
I cannot be expected to look after meself!
我才剛學會阿司匹林瓶蓋要用擰的
I've only just worked out them screw-top lids on them aspirin bottles.
好了 你先把褲子穿上吧
OK. How about you just put some pants on first,
然后再說別的?
then we'll talk about it?
伙計 把手紙用完了我能理解
Mate, running out of bog roll is one fucking thing.
可這也太過分了
This is bang out of order.
氣死我了
It makes my blood boil.
往前走兩分鐘就有垃圾站啊
I mean, there's a municipal recycling facility two minutes down the road.
真是渣滓
It's just scum.
沒人性的渣滓
Sick, inhuman scum.
我們還殺人呢
We kill people.
沒少殺
Frequently.
對
Yeah.
呃 殺人也很了不起的
Well, there's honour in killing people.
亂丟垃圾有個毛的技朮含量啊?
There's no honour in fly-tipping, is there?
喂
Hey!
注意那個人
Check this guy out.
他沒事吧
Is he all right?
你沒事吧 伙計?
You all right, mate?
你還好嗎?      他好像挺友好的?
How you doing?        Oh, he looks friendly, doesn't he?
你還好吧 沒事吧你?
How you doing? You all right, mate?
哎喲 還挺缺愛呢
Oh, shit! He's a bit huggy.
兩塊糖 牛奶加兩塊糖
Two sugars. Milk and two sugars.
牛奶加兩塊糖 快給他倒杯茶...
Milk and two sugars! Get the man a cup of tea immediately bef...
我了個大操的
Oh, my fucking God.
是他 魯迪二號
It's him! It's Rudy 2!
你去哪了 誰把你變成這樣的?
Where have you been? Who's done this to you?
能肯定是他嗎?
Are we absolutely sure it's him?
開什么玩笑? 看
Are you fucking kidding me, man? Look!
他看著有80了 可能還不止呢
He's got to be about 80. Maybe even more.
你記得出了什么事嗎?
Do you remember what happened to you?
哦
Oh.
是你      對
It's you.        Yeah.
一直喜歡你
Always liked you.
下雨天 你的頭發好漂亮
It's raining. Your hair's so pretty...
濕濕的好漂亮
when it's wet.
老天 這貨真是個呆子
Jesus Christ. The man's a fucking vegetable.
我告訴你怎么回事 是風暴
I tell you what's happened here. The storm.
肯定跟風暴有關
This will be something to do with the storm.
真的?      對
Really?        Yeah.
你覺得是?      嗯
You think so?        Mm-hm.
多謝你的線索 馬普爾小姐
Well, thanks for the heads-up, Miss Marple.
也許是因為
Maybe it's something to do
他去的那個超能力互助小組
with that super-power support group he's been going to.
他到底去那種小組干什么?
So, what does he need with a support group, anyway?
講出你的感受 這是示弱的第一步
Talking about your feelings - first sign of weakness.
你應該悶在心里
You should bottle that up inside you
把憤恨憋成鐵板一塊
till it becomes a solid mass of anger and resentment.
我叔叔彼得就是這么做的
That's what my Uncle Peter did.
沒錯 他喝酒喝死了 可這不是重點
Admittedly, he drank himself to death, but that's not the...point.
喂?
Hello?
他餓了
He's hungry.
火腿 雞蛋
Gammon and egg,
還有魚 還有...
and fish and...
他要火腿
He wants gammon.
我也沒辦法 從售貨機給他弄點東西
Well, I don't know. Get him some from a vending machine?
趕快
'OK, hurry up.'
這都應該是你的事 不是我的
You need to be the one dealing with this, not me.
哦
Oh...
各位 就是這里了      好
Guys, this is it.        Right.
什么計划?
What's the plan?
計划是...我們進去
The plan is...we go in there
問問誰把魯迪二號變成了老頭
and we ask 'em which one turned Rudy 2 into an old man.
什么爛計划      是嗎?
Shit plan.        Is it?
如果魯迪二號常來 他們會以為你是他
If Rudy 2's a regular at this group, they're going to think you're him.
進去臥底 假裝成他
Go undercover, pretend to be him
凶手看見你一定會驚訝
and whoever did it'll be surprised to see you.
他們會自動暴露的
They'll give themselves away.
太天才了 我需要這些對嗎?
That is genius. Here's what I need, right?
我需要假胡子 一副眼鏡
I need a beard. I need some glasses.
我需要煙斗 斗篷 再找根拐棍
I need a pipe. I want a cloak. Get me a staff of some kind.
你需要像二號那樣
You need to look like Rudy 2,
不然他們就不會以為你是他了
or they're not gonna think you're him.
這家伙 中考八門合格
This guy, eight GCSEs.
我們去臥底吧
Let's go undercover.
魯迪二號 你近來可好?
Rudy 2. How you doing?
我想你們一定...見到我很驚訝吧
I would imagine you're... quite surprised to see me, guy.
也沒有啊 你每周二都會來嘛
Not really. Um... you always come on a Tuesday.
只能說 老習慣成自然
Let's just say that old habits... die hard.
"老"習慣
OLD...habits.
我叫費恩      很高興見到你 嗨
I'm Finn.        Nice to meet you. Hi.
別理我 我是來蹭餅干吃的
Oh, don't worry about me. I'm just here for the biscuits.
她確實是
She is.
你有什么能力?
So, what's your power?
隔空...      他會產奶
Teleke...        Milky nipples.
嗯?      產奶
Hm?        Milky nipples.
他只要一撒謊 乳頭就出奶
Cos every time he tells a lie, he just expresses milk from his nipples.
太荒謬了 他很尷尬
It's ridiculous. He's very embarrassed about it.
抱歉失陪了
Now, you're going to have to excuse us,
我們還得跟其他人說話呢
cos we do have other people we need to speak to.
費利
Finlay.
什么叫他媽的產奶?
What was all that with the fucking milky nipples?
計划是怎樣的 費恩 還記得嗎?
What was the plan, Finn? Can you remember it?
計划是 我們不暴露真實的能力
The plan was, we don't tell anyone what our real powers are.
計划里沒有這部分
That was nothing to do with the plan.
沒有嗎?      沒有
Was it not?        No!
認真聽我說 兄弟
Now, listen to me, dude, seriously.
這里有個人知道魯迪二號的事 我建議分頭找
Someone here knows something about Rudy 2. I suggest we just split up.
嗯 我覺得我們應該...      滾開
Yeah, I think we should just...       Fuck off.
為什么餅干旁邊有只烏龜?
Why is there a turtle by the biscuits?
他每周都來 是個有超能力的人
He turns up every week. It's someone with a power.
這里面有個人?
There's someone inside of there?
對
Yeah.
他叫馬克
His name's Mark.
你好啊 兄弟
All right, mate?
不用不好意思
You don't have to be embarrassed.
關于你的...能力
About your, um... Your power.
你呢 你的能力是什么?      我? 哦
How about you? What's... What's your power?        Me? Oh.
一言...難盡 我不想說
It's, er...it's complicated. I don't really like to talk about it.
沒關系 不想說不勉強
It's all right. You don't have to, if you don't want to.
問題是 別的人...
The thing is, other people...
總是亂猜我的...
make certain assumptions about my...
性取向 而且...
...sexuality, and...
怎么 他們以為你是同性戀?
What, they... They think you're gay?
對 我覺得他們是這么以為的
Yeah, yeah. I...I guess they do.
那...你是同性戀嗎?
And...a-are you gay?
不是
No!
現在你知道了
Now you know.
不是吧
Fuck off!
你... 你真的出不了柜了
You're... You're literally trapped in the closet?
太好笑了吧?
How funny's that?
而且非常嚴重
And also very serious.
太傷人了
Quietly poignant.
沒錯
Yeah.
其實 我有個朋友能移除超能力
Actually, I've got a friend who can take powers.
他怎么移除 有什么辦法?
How does he take powers? How does it work?
我讓他自己告訴你細節吧
I'll let him fill you in on the details.
啊 你會愛死他的 他叫亞歷克斯
Ah. You're gonna love him. His name's Alex.
在做社區服務      太好了
He's on community service.        Great.
還馬普爾小姐 傻逼
Miss Marple? The prick.
嘿      我操
(Hey.        Fucking hell!)
就是她
That's her.
她也老 他也老 我臥底去了
She's old, he's old. I'm going undercover, man.
就是她了      好 等等
This is it.        OK, wait.
哦 人都到齊了 那就開始吧
Ooh, er...OK, everyone's here. Let's make a start.
該死
Shit.
嗨 魯迪二號      嗯 你也好
Hi, Rudy 2.        Yeah. All right, you.
魯迪二號 上次你在跟我們說魯迪一號
Rudy 2. Last time, you were telling us about Rudy 1.
是嗎?
Was I?
我 我不記得了
I don't... I...I don't remember.
好吧 你說你為他的行為感到尷尬
OK, well, you were telling us you were embarrassed by his behaviour.
你覺得被背叛了 他不肯把你介紹給你們父母
You feel betrayed that he hasn't introduced you to your parents.
這回...機會讓給別人吧 對不對?
Just... Let's just let someone else have a turn, shall we, mate?
就那位怎樣 他看上去麻煩挺大的 是不是?
What about him over there? He looks like he's got issues, don't he?
你說有時候你以他為恥
Y-You were saying that at times you're ashamed of him,
他讓你覺得丟人
that he makes you feel ashamed.
讓下一個人說 拜托了好嗎
Just fucking move on! For fuck's sake, man!
哈
Ha.
化得整個座椅都是
It melted all over the seats.
抱歉 什么化了?
Sorry? What did?
我爸爸的車 真皮座椅
My dad's car with the leather seats.
我們開車去海邊 巧克力化了一座椅
We were goin' to t'seaside and chocolate melted all over the seats,
可他沒生氣
but he wasn't angry.
他又給我買了一塊
He just bought me another one.
操 你他媽的干了什么
FUCK! What the fuck are you doing,
背著我說我壞話
talking shit about me behind my fucking back?
你嫌我丟人? 你還有臉嫌我丟人?
YOU'RE ashamed? You're fucking ashamed?
你個垃圾      怎么...放開他
You fucking shambles!       What the...? Get off him!
傻逼      走開
Fucking mug.        Get off!
你沒事了 沒事的
You're all right. You're OK.
來吧兄弟 這邊走
Come on, dude! This way.
他穿的什么?
What is he wearing?
什么? 哦 挺好的短褲
What? They're nice shorts, them.
運動鞋? 怎么 要帶他到公園去跑步?
Trainers? What, he's going for a kick-about in the park, is he?
我不管他干什么 他愛怎樣怎樣
I don't care what he does. He can do what he wants!
各位 我給大家介紹個人
Guys. There's someone I'd like you to meet.
我在昨晚小組聚會上認識的
I found him at the group last night.
這里面有個人      抱歉 等等
There's a person in there.       Sorry? Hang on.
你找到一只烏龜
You found a turtle,
就這么直接拿回家去了?
and you just thought that you'd pick him up and take him home?
你拐走了一只烏龜?
You abducted a turtle?
准確說是只陸龜
Well, technically, it's a tortoise.
猜猜誰跟蹤那個互助組的老妖婆回了家
Guess who followed the evil old woman home from the support group
拿到了她家地址?
and got her address?
是這位英雄 天才呀 真他媽天才
This guy did! Genius. The lad's a frigging genius.
八門過關 英語 數學 還有法語
Eight GCSEs. English, maths and French.
他去哪了?      誰?
Where's he gone, then?        Who?
去哪? 該死
Gone? Shit!
喂 伙計 你干嘛呢?
Oi! Mate, what you doing?
喂 喂      傻逼 你去哪?
Hey, hey.        Idiot. Where you going?
是這邊啊笨蛋 哦 上帝
It's this way. You moron... Oh, Christ.
這他媽又是誰?
And who the fuck might this be?
呃...      怎么了 貓把你舌頭叼走了?
Er...       What's the matter? Cat got your tongue?
不介紹我們認識嗎?
Aren't you going to introduce us?
操 我不知他是誰 他跟我無關
Shit, I don't know who he is. He's nothing to do with me.
他是我爺爺
He's my grandad.
這些人曾拋頭顱洒熱血 團結一心
Men like this fought in wars, cheek by jowl,
趴在地上 在泥漿 鮮血和恐懼中爬行
belly-down, crawling through the mud, the blood, and the fear.
為了誰?
And for what?
嗯?
Eh?
涂發蠟的男孩
Boys with hair straighteners.
穿緊身褲 挺著松弛大屁股的女孩
Girls in jeggings, with their flabby arses hanging out!
見到您我榮幸之至 先生
It was my very real privilege to have met you, sir.
你得負起責任來 他是你的責任
You need to step up! He is your responsibility!
好 好 我會解決的
Oh, fine! Fine. I'll... I'll sort it.
操
Fuck!
好了 進去吧 瞧這里多完美
Right, just get you in here. Perfect. Look at this place.
就...
Just...
就坐這里別動 好啦
Just get you sat down there. There we go.
這里面有什么?
And what do we have in here?
瞧呀
Look at that.
你真走運 給吧
What a lucky fella! There you go.
甜筒 椅子 這簡直是里茲大飯店了
Cornetto, chair. It's like the frigging Ritz in here.
好好玩 別一下全吃完了 一會兒見
Have fun. Don't eat it all at once. See you in a bit.
你是亞歷克斯嗎?
Are you Alex?
你朋友說你能移除超能力
Your mate said you'd take my power.
什么朋友?
What mate?
乳頭會產奶那個
Your mate with the milky nipples.
抱歉 誰?      矮個子的
What? Sorry?        He was short.
哦 費恩 小猴崽子
Oh, Finn. You monkey-faced fuck.
呃 請別介意 但我不幫男的
Er...look, no offence, mate, but I don't really do blokes.
這是什么意思?
What's that supposed to mean?
就是我不想和男人上床
It means I'm not into having sex with men.
你以為我是基佬?
What, you think I'm gay?
我不管你是什么
I don't really care what you are.
聽著 我才不是基
Look, I'm not gay!
就是這里 她叫瑪吉
This is it. Her name's Maggie.
好吧 瑪吉
All right, Maggie.
出來混總是要還的 婊子
It's time to pay the fucking piper, biatch.
我操
Bosh!
你干什么?
What are you doing?
我以為這是計划的一部分
Well, I thought it was part of the plan!
我們直接敲門就好
We could have just knocked.
沒時間敲門了 費利 還要我說出來嗎
It's too late to frigging knock now, Finlay, for crying out loud!
沒時間敲門了吧?
IS it too late to knock?
操 我現在敲吧 看她怎么說
Shit, I'm just gonna knock, man, see what she's saying.
有人嗎?
Yoo-hoo?
她來了 我怎么說?
Here she comes. What do I say?
說對不起
Say sorry.
你好嗎 親愛的?
All right, love?
你為什么打破我的門?
Why did you break my door?
因為我...
Because I...
我以為你摔倒了...
I thought you'd fallen...over...
扭了腰
..and broken your hip.
來幫我把拼圖拼了 然后把鎖修好
Well, you can fix that lock when you've helped me with my jigsaw.
哦 上帝
Oh...God.
我有只貓
I have a cat.
她可能會想吃你的奶
She may try to drink from your nipples.
你干什么?      合不上啊
What are you doing?        It just fucking won't fit.
首先要找到邊 再朝里推進
You need to find the edges first, work from the outside in.
這是常識      哦 拜托...
Basic puzzling.        Oh, just...
拼你的拼圖 兄弟
the jigsaw, man.
我去臥底了
I'm going undercover.
問問她知道什么
I'm going to see what she knows.
好嗎?      好
Yeah?        Yes.
所以 瑪吉
So...Maggie.
你一定... 沒想到會見到我吧
I suppose you're... quite surprised to see me.
不是嗎?
Aren't you?
今天周三 你每周三都來
It's Wednesday. You always come Wednesday.
手伸出來
Hands.
哦
Oh...
所以...
So...
那個混蛋魯迪一號最近對你如何?
how's that awful Rudy 1 treating you?
他不是混蛋 他就... 就是有點被誤會
He's not awful. He's just... He's a bit misunderstood, that's all.
我說多少遍了 你該離開他
You should leave him. I'm sick of telling you.
也許他需要我
Well, maybe he needs me.
也許他該學著照顧自己了
And perhaps it's time he learnt to look after himself.
恕我直言
Well, with all due respect,
也許你他媽該學會少管閑事 瑪格麗特
perhaps it's time you minded your own fucking beeswax, Margaret.
我不喜歡你今天的腔調 魯迪二號
I don't think I care for your tone today, Rudy 2.
對不起 我不該罵人
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have sworn.
去臥室
Bedroom.
把淺粉色線團拿來
There's a ball of pale pink.
快去呀
Well, go on.
耶
Yes.
四角找全了
All four corners.
哼
Huh.
這都是有意義的
They all mean something.
是什么呢?
Who knows what?
他們總會知道的
They'll find out eventually.
誰會?
Who will?
毛衣上的人
The people on the jumpers.
這是他們的未來
It's their future.
你該走了
You'd better be going.
你周三不是還要見提姆嗎?
Don't you usually meet up with Tim on a Wednesday?
哦 提姆 當然
Oh! Tim! Course I do!
提姆 提姆可不等人 沒錯
Tim...Tim. Tim waits for no man, as it t'were.
不過說真的
Seriously, though.
我行事歷丟了 我忘了
I've mislaid my old Filofax. Can't remember.
在哪見提姆來著?
Where exactly do I meet Tim?
她能織出預言
She knits the future.
真是非傳統的能力啊 是吧?
It's not exactly your classic super-power, is it?
嗨
Hey.
我得跟你談談
I need to talk to you.
哦
Oh.
所以
So...
提姆? 我想...你見到我一定很意外吧
Tim? I suppose you're, er... quite surprised to see me.
我們單獨談一分鐘
Give us a minute.
別走 你去哪 兄弟? 坐這別動
Stay. Where you going, dude? Stay there.
提姆 提姆?
Tim? Tim?
又發生了      嗯?
It happened again.        Hm?
我今早醒來 發現了這個
I woke up this morning and I found this.
哦我操... 你是不是... 這是槍哎
Oh, for fuck... Do you...? What? Fucking gun!
我不知道哪來的 反正肯定沒好事
I don't know where it came from, but it can't be good.
幫幫我
Help me.
求你 告訴我該怎么辦
Just please tell me what to do.
好吧 不是我要告訴你該怎么辦
All right, instead of me telling you what I think you should do,
也許你該告訴我 你打算怎么辦 提姆
maybe you should tell me what YOU think you should do, Tim.
我得彈一下手環
I need to snap the band.
提醒自己 這是現實
Remind myself that this is real.
這不是游戲
That it's not a game.
好主意 那就彈吧
Cool. Well, then, just snap it.
彈手環 提醒你自己這是現實 然后...
You snap the band, remind yourself it's real and...
怎么了 哥們?
Well, what, dude?
什么...
What...?
什么情況? 你有點緊張啊
What's the matter, dude? You're getting a bit twitchy.
別拿出來 我操拜托 快拿開
Let's not get that out... For fuck's sake, put it away.
他們會報警的
They'll ring the fucking police.
不不不 我操 拜托
No, no, no, no, no! For fuck...
快彈手環 快把它拿開
Snap the band, dude! Put it away!
快他媽彈手環 提姆 快給我彈
Fucking snap the band, Tim. Snap the fucking band!
快他媽彈手環 快他媽彈手環
Snap the fucking band. Snap the fucking band.
把槍收回包里去
Put the fucking gun in the bag.
老兄 快把槍收起來 老天在上 提姆 我操
Dude, put the fucking gun in the bag. For Christ's sake, Tim! Shit!
謝謝
Thanks.
哦 不客氣
Oh! You're welcome.
你真是個好朋友
You're a good friend.
你也不壞 費利 把那玩意喝掉
You're not so bad yourself. Finlay, dude, drink that shit up.
他到底為啥幫這些人?
Why the fuck does he help these people?
他連說都沒說過 他誰也沒告訴
And he doesn't even go on about it, he doesn't tell anyone.
我捐了2毛錢給抗癌中心 至今我還挂在嘴邊
I?I gave 20p to Cancer Research. I'm still going on about it.
你沒事吧?      我有件事要做
Are you all right?        There's something I need to do.
我回頭打給你      好
I'll call you later.        OK.
他在這兒呢
Here he is.
狡猾的銀狐狸 你去哪...
The silver fox, where...
我操
Shit!
你把他關壁櫥里了
You locked him in a fucking cupboard!
哼 理論上講那不是壁櫥
Huh. Well, technically, that's not a cupboard.
那是個儲藏室啊 對吧?
That's a bloody storeroom, innit?
不 這不是開玩笑
No, this isn't a fucking joke.
我就走開五分鐘
It was only five minutes while I was...
所有事都要我管 所以...
I was taking care of everything. So...
你走開五分鐘去撒尿我也不管
I don't care if it's for five minutes while you go for a piss.
好吧 老天啊 我道歉好不好
All right. Jesus Christ, I'm fucking sorry, like.
你看看他
Look at him!
這不是玩笑
This is not a joke!
這不是生活中一點小麻煩
This is not some minor inconvenience to your day!
這不是外人
It's not some random old man!
他是魯迪二號 你的一部分
He's Rudy 2 and he's a part of you!
好吧
All right.
操
(Shit.)
對不起 兄弟 對不起
I'm sorry, man. Oh, shit, I'm sorry.
別這樣 沒事的
Oh, no, it's all right.
別傷心
Don't be sad.
哦 我好累
Oh, I'm tired.
去睡一覺吧 我去弄我們的晚餐
Go and get some bloody shut-eye. I'll go and get our dinner.
我們看著電視一起吃 好嗎?      好
We'll watch it in front of t'TV, yeah?        Yeah.
是我
It's me.
強森先生      是你
Mr Johnson.        You.
你回來了
You came back.
看看你
Look at you.
我沒打算變成這樣的
I didn't mean for it to happen like this.
我愛她
I love her.
我一輩子都在等待這種感覺
I've waited my whole life to feel this way...
現在我得到了她 我...
..and now I've got her, I...
我不能再讓她走了
I can't just let her go again.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
再見 魯迪二號      幫幫我
Goodbye, Rudy 2.        Help me.
幫幫我 幫幫我 幫幫我
Help me. Help me! Help me!
他來了 幫幫我
He's here! Help me!
幫幫我
Help me!
你還好吧 兄弟?
Are you all right, mate?
他來了 他來了
He was here! He was here!
誰來了? 冷靜點      他來了
Who was here? Calm down.        He was here!
他還在這里 他還在      冷靜
He's still here! He's still here!        Calm down.
冷靜
Calm down.
誰來了?
Who was in here?
我的茶 我要我的茶
My tea. I wanted my tea.
哦 上帝
Oh, Christ.
沒事了 兄弟 我回來了
It's all right, mate. I'm here now.
我回來了 我不會再離開你的
I'm here now and I won't leave you.
好吧 在我找到辦法把他復原之前
Now then, until I can figure out how to get him back to normal,
我們得輪流照看他
we're all gonna take turns helping,
所以我列了個簡單的輪班表
so I've drawn out a simple rota system.
按顏色標明 手寫的
That's colour-coded and handwritten.
還壓膜 真不錯
Laminated. Nice touch.
謝謝
Thank you.
這里有煮過的糖 給你的 兄弟
In here we have boiled sweets. They're for you, dude.
電視指南 你們看 我把有關的都圈起來了
TV guide. You'll note I've ringed all the relevant programmes.
謀殺診斷書(電視劇) 斯諾克
Diagnosis Murder, snooker,
居家尋寶秀 古董玩家
Cash In The Attic, and Bargain Hunt.
這位杰出的先生
This fine figure of a man
曾無數次照料過我
has looked after me more times than I care to remember,
我還要說
and I tell you something else -
他也照料過你們每個人
he'd have done the same for each and every one of you,
因為他真是個大好人
because he's a bloody good bloke.
現在 我們事情很多 不如就動手做吧
Now, we've got a lot to do. So I think we should get on it.
動起來吧 各位
Let's do this. Come on, guys.
# 我聽說了昨晚的好消息
# Well, I heard about the good news that happened last night
# 哦 耶 它帶來了歡樂
# Oh, yeah, and it brings out joy... #
# 和深深的幸福
# And happiness gone deep inside
# 對 我真高興 有這些好消息
# Yes, I'm glad I'm glad of some good news
# 昨晚的好消息
# That's happened last night
# 所以別驚訝
# So don't you marvel
# 這些事注定要發生
# These things must come to pass... #
亞歷克斯 幫我個小忙好嗎?
Um...Alex, will you do me a quick favour?
能不能操我的烏龜?
Will you fuck my tortoise?
給我一分鐘 考慮一下
Um...just give me a minute to think about...that.
實際上 用不了一分鐘 答案是不行
Er...actually, I don't need a full minute. It's a no.
這是個人 他叫馬克
It's a man and his name's Mark.
他被困在里面 沒法逃脫
He's trapped in here and he can't get out.
真是悲劇啊      嗯
That is really tragic.        Mm.
可我還是不會操你的烏龜
But I'm still not fucking your tortoise.
你根本不理解 對嗎?
You have no idea, do you?
我知道了我的超能力 一點用都沒有
I found out what my power is and it's totally useless.
根本誰也幫不了
There's nothing I can do to help anyone.
可你 你能作出改變
But you... You can make a difference.
我們中只有你能改變別人的人生
You're the only one out of us who can actually change people's lives.
可你做了什么呢? 袖手旁觀
And what are you doing about it? Nothing.
坐在那一動不動
It's just sat there in your pants.
把超能力用起來 亞歷克斯
Use your power, Alex.
幫助別人
Help people.
做個超級英雄
Be a superhero.
操了這只烏龜吧 亞歷克斯
Fuck the tortoise, Alex.
齊活了 你看
Right! Here we go, look,
干淨衣服 隨你怎么弄臟
clean clothes. You're gonna be beating 'em off with a shitty stick, you are.
給你吧 我們來...
There you go. All right, let's get...
你穿的什么東西?
What the frigging hell are you wearing?
毛衣 瑪吉給我織的
My jumper. Maggie made it for me.
他說冷 我在沙發底下找到的
He was cold. I found it under the sofa.
這他媽是我啊 是我啊 我在飛 你看
That's fucking me! That's me! I'm fucking flying! Look!
你說什么?
What you talking about?
這是未來的我 我就知道 我就知道
It's the future. That is me, that. I fucking knew...I knew it!
哦 這只是件毛衣
Oh, it's just a jumper.
那個女人能織出預言 這是我們 瞧
This woman, she knits the future. That is us, look.
好吧 怎么只有四個人?
All right. How comes there's only four of us?
肯定漏了費恩
She had to miss Finn out, obviously.
那么小的人怎么織啊?
No-one can knit that fucking small, can they?
我們送他上床睡覺吧 手舉起來
Let's get him... Let's get him ready for bed. Hands in the air.
哦吼
Woo-hoo!
給你整整領子
Let me just sort your collar out.
好了 衣服脫下來 准備好了嗎?
Right, let's get this off. Are you ready?
他去哪了 他去哪了?
Where's he gone? Where's he gone?
天啊 他去哪了? 在這兒呢
Oh, my God, where's he gone? There he is.
好了      給他講講巧克力的事
Right.       Oh, tell him about the chocolate.
什么巧克力?
What chocolate?
皮座椅 你去海邊的時候
The leather seats. You were going to the seaside.
巧克力化在座椅上了
Chocolate all over seats.
我爸的車 皮座椅
Me dad's car with the leather seats.
哦 閉嘴 沒人愛聽這個 無聊死了
Oh, shut up, man. No-one wants to hear about that. It's boring.
不 我就愛聽
No. I like it.
是焦糖夾心巧克力棒
It was a...a Curly Wurly.
我把它放在...短褲屁股兜里
And I put it in my back pocket of my... Of my shorts.
我坐在上面 從家里一直坐到公路上
And I sat on it all the way from home until the motorway.
那個假期可開心了
That were a bloody brilliant holiday!
我不記得... 你知道嗎 我都忘了
I can't... D'you know, I forgot about that.
我把我的小坦克埋在海灘上
Er...I buried me tank on t'beach.
我操 那坦克
The fucking... The tank.
我最愛的坦克 過生日別人送的 對吧?
I got... I loved that tank. I got it for my birthday, didn't I?
媽媽和爸爸把海灘挖了個遍
Me mam and dad, they dug up the whole beach,
怎么也找不到
but they couldn't find it.
15年后 他們回去 回到原來的海灘 對吧?
15 years later, they went back, didn't they, to t'same beach?
他們吃著三明治
They were eating their sandwiches...
那里有個男孩
..and there was a boy.
正在挖洞
He was making a hole.
挖到了我的坦克 我的小坦克又回來了
They found my tank. I got my bloody tank back.
你要看電視嗎?
Do you want to watch TV?
好      好嗎?
Er...yeah.        Yeah?
就這么辦      好
Yeah, all right, then.        Good.
我去拿薯片好不好? 行
I'll get the crisps, shall I? All right?
諷刺的是 為了讓我拿走你的能力
The irony is that for me to take your power,
為了讓你從柜里出來
and for you to stop being trapped in closets,
我們得來次肛交
we need to have anal sex.
嗯
Mm.
事先說清楚 我和你上床是因為你不是基
Just so we're clear, am I fucking you because you're not gay
而且想移除你的超能力?
and you're just sick of having your power?
還是因為你就是基
Or am I fucking you because you are gay
卻不想被別人知道?
and you just don't want anyone to know about it?
有點難回答
It's a head-scratcher.
是因為我爸
It's my dad.
他不接受我
He won't accept me.
那他是個傻逼
Well, then, he's a dick.
有問題的是他 不是你
He's the one who needs helping, not you.
我該走了
I should go.
不想有空一起喝一杯?
I don't suppose you'd fancy a drink some time?
盡管交配已經結束
'And though their mating is now over,
雄性卻會開始審視其交媾行為
'the male will often begin to review his amorous...'
額 你在干什么?      沒什么
Eurgh. What you doing?        N-Nothing.
該死 對不起 我以為...是他的脖子
Shit. I'm sorry. I just thought... I thought it was his neck.
從皮毛中捉出虱子 于是...
'..picking fleas and tics out of his fur and so...'
好啦 你個二逼 快喝掉
Right, come on, you, buggerlugs, drink up.
"新居大改造"要開始了 快去看啊
Homes Under The Hammer's about to start. Let's have it.
來吧 可別錯過了 對不對?
Come on. We don't want to miss that, do we?
你干什么?      我覺得他心臟病犯了
What are you doing, man?        I think he's having a heart attack.
我們怎么辦? 操
What do we do? Fuck!
快來人啊
Somebody help!
快來人啊      吸氣
Somebody help!        Breathe!
上帝耶穌老天爺啊 怎么辦?
Jesus fucking Christ! What do we do?
退后
Stand back.
你是醫生嗎?      我是電工
Are you a doctor?        I'm an electrician.
他沒呼吸了
He's not fucking breathing!
清除
Clear!
哦操
Oh, shit.
你沒事吧 兄弟?
Are you all right, mate?
你沒事吧?
Are you all right?
你沒事吧?      他沒事
Are you all right?        He is.
沒關系 哥們 我在這 沒關系了
It's all right, man, I'm here now. It's all right, bud.
謝謝 謝謝你
Thanks. Thank you.
把他扶起來
Get him up.
費恩陪著他 他睡著了
Finn's with him. He's gone off to sleep.
他會死的 對嗎?
He's gonna die, isn't he?
不是... 不是現在
Not... Not now.
很快
Soon.
我會變成孤身一人
And I'm going to be all on my own.
等我變成這樣 誰來照顧我呢?
Who's going to look after me when I get like that?
也許你會遇見合適的人 成家 生子
Maybe you'll meet someone, settle down, have kids.
像普通人那樣
Like a normal person.
誰會樂意和我成家?
Who'd want to settle down with me?
嗯?
Hm?
我爺爺老了之后 我們給他找了個療養院
When my grandad got old, we found him a home.
他在那挺開心的
He was happy there.
也許這是他最好的歸宿
Maybe it's the best thing for him.
對大家都好
For everyone.
會有人照顧他 你想看他就去看
They'll look after him. You can visit him when you like.
對
Yeah.
你會跟我們一起去嗎?
Will you come with us?
我當然會
Of course I will.
我們只用給你弄台電視 几張海報
All we need t'do is get you a bloody TV. Couple of posters.
這可是單身公寓啊 瞧瞧 里外套間
It's a fucking bachelor pad. That's what this... Look at this. En suite.
還有撒尿的池子
Cheeky wee in the sink.
如果你凌晨四點想吃火腿鱷梨三明治
And if you fancy a ham and avocado sandwich at four in the morning,
還有客房服務 隨叫隨到
you got your room service there, cheeky tug.
他來了 他來看我了
He came. H-He came to see me.
喂 聽我說
Oi, listen to me.
我會來看你的
I'LL come and see you.
我會早也來 晚也來
I'm gonna be here so often,
直到你見我就想吐
you're gonna be sick of the friggin' sight of me.
我馬上就回來看你
I'll see you soon.
怎樣?
Yeah?
好嗎?
All right?
我們走吧 去新的地方
Let's just get away. We'll go somewhere.
從頭開始
Start again.
去哪?
Where?
我不知道 去哪都行
I don't know. Anywhere.
這里有我太多的回憶
There's too many memories for me here.
或者
Or...
不如我們
..how about
哪也不去
we don't go anywhere...
就去喝一杯?
and we just go for a drink instead?
我又去你的互助組了 什么也沒問出來
I went back to your group. No-one knows anything.
操 對不起 兄弟 我盡力了
Shit, I'm...I'm sorry, man. I tried.
可我后來又去了爸媽家
You know, but then I went to Mum and Dad's house
給你帶了個禮物
and I've got you a present.
怎樣?
Eh?
哦 對
Oh, yeah.
他們翻遍了整個海灘
They dug up the whole beach.
他們正吃著三明治...
They were having their sandwiches...
沒錯
They did.
你留著 好嗎?
I want you to have it, yeah?
你? 我沒想到你會來
You? I wasn't expecting to see you.
是嗎 為什么? 抱歉 為什么沒想到?
Really? Why? Sorry, why might that be?
強森先生不在這了 他走了
Mr Johnson isn't here any more. He's gone.
對不起 我... 我行事歷丟了
I'm sorry, I just...I seem to have mislaid the old Filofax.
你說的哪個強森先生?
Which Mr Johnson do you mean?
因為我常來看的有好几個 所以...
Cos I help a few on a regular basis, that's all, so...
倫﹒強森 我真的很擔心他
Len Johnson. I'm really worried about him.
我們查了所有醫院 就是找不到他
We've tried all the hospitals, but there's no sign of him.
謝謝
Thanks
(倫﹒強森)
沒事的
It's OK.
不用驚慌
There's no need to panic.
我們要在一起了
We're going to be together.
我和娜奧米
Me and Naomi.
我知道你會為我們高興的
I know you'd be happy for us.
可我不能冒險讓你毀了一切
But I can't risk you ruining everything.
你要把他怎樣?
What the fuck are you doing to him, man?
他是我的朋友
He's my friend.
我的超能力 可以和人互換年齡
My power. I can swap ages with people.
魯迪二號愿意每周和我互換一小時
Rudy 2 used to let me switch with him for an hour a week
讓我享受一下年輕的滋味
just to give me a break from being an old man.
我對她一見鐘情
I loved her from the minute I saw her.
娜奧米
Naomi.
我的護士
She was my nurse.
我終生沒結婚 我...
I never got married. I...
一直沒能找到真愛 直到今天
..never found my true love... until now.
如果我告訴她你的行為呢?
What if I was to tell her what you've been doing?
如果我給他看你的照片會怎樣?
What if I showed her the photo of you?
那時她就明白了 你是怎樣的人
Cos then she'd see you for what you really are.
求你別告訴她
Please don't tell her.
你還好吧 兄弟?
You all right, mate?
沒事了 兄弟
It's all right, mate.
沒事了 沒事了
It's all right, it's all right.
動手吧
Do it.
快動手 不然我就告訴她一切
Do it or I'll tell her everything.
握住他的手 好了
Take his hand. It's all right.
快動手吧
Come on.
好啦 朋友 好了
All right, pal. There.
你沒事了
You're all right.
現在
Now then,
你得好好謝謝我了 年輕人 對不對?
I believe a thanks is in order, innit, young man? Ha-ha-ha!
你把我關壁櫥里了
You locked me in a cupboard.
那才不是壁櫥 那是儲藏室
No, it wasn't a cupboard, it was a storeroom,
我還給你擦屁股 喂你吃黃油糖
and I wiped your arse and I gave you butterscotch
還讓你看他媽的斯諾克
and I let you watch the friggin' snooker.
我不愛看斯諾克      忘恩負義的東西
I don't like the snooker.        You ungrateful fucker!
我開玩笑的 你做得挺好
Nah, I'm only kidding. You did great.
我走了 伙計 周五見
I'm going now, mate. See you on Friday.
來吧 進來吧 軟蛋
Hey, come on. Give over, you soft shite.
快過來 歡迎回家
Come here, come on, welcome home.
所以 你幫我勾搭的那個基佬
So...about that gay guy that you hooked me up with.
哦對      對
Oh! Yeah.        Oh, yeah(!)
我得說聲謝謝
I just wanted to say thanks.
幫助別人的感覺不錯
It felt good helping somebody.
你知道嗎 我覺得這就是我超能力的用法
You know, I think this is what I'm supposed to do with my power.
做個... 真正的英雄
You know, be like a... A proper hero.
都得謝謝你 嗯?
And all thanks to you, eh?
嗯 別客氣
Yeah, pleasure.
等等 現在你肯幫別人了 能不能...
So, hang on. Now you're into helping people, would you...?
不行 還是不操你的烏龜
No. I won't shag your tortoise.
早安 馬克 你睡得好嗎?
Morning, Mark. Did you sleep well?
回頭見
(See you later.)
你還好嗎?      嗯
You all right?        Mm.
我有點想他 是不是很奇怪?
Is it weird that I miss him?
照顧人的感覺挺好的
It was nice having someone to look after.
不 我不覺得奇怪
No, I don't think it's weird.
知道嗎? 如果我不是這么個混蛋 我會...
Do you know what? If I wasn't such a total fuck-up, I'd...
我大概會約你喝一杯 你會答應的
I'd probably ask you out for a drink and you'd say yeah
因為 我不會是你現在看到的這個混蛋
because, well, I wouldn't be the mess that stands before you now.
我會是...另一個人 你知道 一個...
I'd be... I'd be someone different, you know, someone...
一個好人
You know, someone good.
我們會在一起度過特別開心的時光
And we'd end up having this really amazing time together and...
也許... 也許還會變成男女朋友
I dunno, we might even end up as boyfriend and girlfriend.
也許最后 我也不會把一切搞成一團糟
And it wouldn't end up with me just fucking it up all the time
在你眼里變成個人渣
and you thinking I'm a total cunt.
絕對不會那樣的 結果會很圓滿
It wouldn't be like that at all. It'd be nice.
我們會幸福地... 在一起
And we'd be happy...together.
我不知道
And, I don't know, fucking hell,
沒准有一天 我們還會養個狗什么的
one day we might even get a dog or summat.
那好吧
All right, then.
什么好吧?
All right, then, what?
你剛請我喝一杯 我答應了
You just asked me out for a drink and I said yes.
好吧
Yeah.
嗯
Huh.
薩姆 薩姆
Sam. Sam.
我想給你看點東西
I wanna show you something.
那是我嗎?
Is that me?
對 我覺得是
Yeah. I think so.
下面這個帶閃電的女孩
And this girl down here with the lightning bolts.
我犯了心臟病 被她救了
I had an heart attack. She saved my life.
樓頂上這個是誰?
Who's that on top of the building?
我不知道      也許是你
I don't know.        Maybe it's you.
說不定我們都能成為超級英雄?
What if we all become superheroes?
我是說 真正的...
I mean, like, you know, proper...
超級英雄
superheroes.
也許這才是我們的宿命
Maybe it's our destiny.
(Echo And The Bunnymen - The Killing Moon)
# 我看見你
# I saw you
# 殘酷地吻了我
# So cruelly you kissed me
# 你的雙唇如夢如幻
# Your lips a magic world
# 你的天空綴滿寶石
# Your sky all hung with jewels
# 殺人的月色
# The killing moon
# 來得太快
# Will come too soon
# 命運
# Fate
# 讓你身不由己
# Up against your will
# 你會向他俯首稱臣
# You give yourself to him... #
(下集預告)
我覺得是我的朋友莉亞
'I think it was my friend Lia.'
莉亞?
Lia?
我覺得她對我做了什么
'I...I think she did something to me.'
你干什么的?      監督官
What do you do?        Probation worker.
我... 哦 上帝啊
I... Oh, my God.
別搭理我 我是個傻逼
Just don't talk to me. I'm-I'm a twat.
我叫莉亞
I'm...I'm Lia.
是你 不是嗎?
It was you, wasn't it?
我能不能 我要說句話...
Can I just...? Let me just say, in my...
我要為自己說句話... 啊
Let me just say in my defence...
是她 她下載進了亞歷克斯
JESS:  It's her. She's downloaded into Alex.
姑娘們 姑娘們 姑娘們 姑娘們
Girls, girls, girls, girls, girls!
我覺得他走了
I think he's gone.
破爛熊字幕組
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
歡迎加入